American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIg. 1887-1891 APS.Archives.IIg APS.Archives.IIg
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 5, 1888; 9x5; O'Neill, Charles, 1821-1893
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S. 1p. Says that the bill reducing passport fees to one dollar has not become law yet.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Feb. 6, 1888; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning his manuscript on the fauna of the Puerco epoch, and two sketches.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 8, 1888; 7x4-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Concerning address of M.B.Snyder.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Feb. 9, 1888; 8x5; Bache, Richard Meade
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Says that he has the sketches of the [Magellanic] medal and that he is ready to report to the committee.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 9, 1888; 8x5; Uhler, Philip R. (Philip Reese), 1835-1913
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Friendly letter. Thanks for corrected copy of his map.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Feb. 14, 1888; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Stevenson, John J. (John James), 1841-1924
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. Concerning letter to [G.] Meneghini.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 15, 1888; 3x5; John Wanamaker (Firm)
    Phila., L.on postal card. 1p.and add. Says that the chairs were sent this morning.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Feb. 15, 1888; 8x5; Bache, Richard Meade
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p. Asking why he did not hear from him about meeting of committee to whom he is to report. Refers to [L.] Haupt.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Feb. 16, 1888; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Enc.wanting. Sends two manuscripts for publication.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 16, 1888; 3x5; Findlay, William
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add.,end. Asking for information about Volapük, and for conditions of membership in Society.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 16, 1888; 9x5-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.and end. Enc.wanting. Sends two drawings for his paper on the fauna of the Puerco epoch.
  - Letter to Henry W.Phillips [Henry Phillips], Feb. 16, 1888; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Osborn, Henry Fairfield, 1857-1935
    Princeton, L.S.:W[illia]m B.Scott, Henry F.Osborn. 2p. Concerning their paper on Mammalia of the Uinta period. Refers to [O.C.?] Marsh.
  - Letter to librarian of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Feb. 18, 1888; 9x6; G. & B. Westermann Brothers
    New York, L. 1p. Asking for publication by Potts on water sponges.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Feb. 18, 1888; 8x5; Hockley, Thomas, 1839-1892
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Asking favor in re C.B.Moore. Sends pamphlet.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 21, 1888; 8x5; New York Academy of Sciences. Section of Anthropology
    Brooklyn, A.L.S.:Edward C.Mann,president. 1p. Extends invitation to international conference of anthropology at Columbia College.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Feb. 23, 1888; 9x5-1/2; Heilprin, Angelo, 1853-1907
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p.,end. Thanks for publication. Concerning a report on a paper.
  - Letter to Henry F.Osborn, Feb. 24, 1888; 13x8; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. Mutilated. Copy. Concerning mode of publication for the paper he has offered.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 24, 1888; 8x5; Bache, Richard Meade
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Says that he is going to write to Mr. Price [J.S.Price ?] this morning.
  - Letter to [Angelo] Heilprin, Feb. 24?, [1888]; 13x8; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Typed L.S. 1p. Mutilated. Copy. Concerning papers offered for the Transactions of the Society.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Feb. 25, 1888; 6-1/2x4-1/2; Thayer, Russell
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Resignation from Society.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 27, 1888; 9x5-1/2; Battles, Frank
    A.L.S. 1p. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Feb. 27, 1888; 8x5; Bache, Richard Meade
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 3p. Concerning their meeting with Mr.Price [J.S.Price ?].
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Feb. 27, 1888; 9x5-1/2; Stowell, T. B. (Thomas Blanchard), 1846-1927
    Cortland, N.Y., A.L.S. 2p. Enc.wanting. Offers papers on comparative neurology for publication by Society.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], Feb. 27, 1888; 8x5; Bolton, Henry Carrington, 1843-1903
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. Asking if the Society has unpublished letters of Joseph Priestley. On same sheet is short-hand version of letter from Phillips to H.Bolton, Feb.28, 1888.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 27, [1888?]; 8-1/2x5; Brooks, William Keith, 1848-1908
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p. Asking for publications by A.Gatschet on the Baltuk [Beothuk] Indians.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 28, 1888; 3x5; Bache, Richard Meade
    [Phila.], A.L.on postal card S. 1p.,end.,and add. Concerning their meeting with [J.S.?] Price.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Feb. 28, 1888; 8x5; Du Bois, Patterson, 1847-1917
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerning spelling reform.
  - Letter to Prof. H.Carrington Bolton, New York, Feb. 28, 1888; 8x5-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., A.Dr.of L.S.:Henry Phillips,secretary. 1p. Concerning unpublished letters of Joseph Priestley. For short-hand version of same letter, see same sheet as letter from H.C.Bolton to [H.Phillips], Feb 27, 1888.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Feb. 29, 1888; 11x8-1/2; Diplomatic and consular service, German
    Phila., L.S.:Cha[rle]s H.Meyer. 1p. Enc.wanting Forwards letter from P.Steiner on Volapük and Pasilingua.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Feb. 30, [1888?]; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Osborn, Henry Fairfield, 1857-1935
    Princeton, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Says he is hoping soon to submit the manuscript to the publication committee.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 1, 1888; 6-1/2x4-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking for botanical publications. Refers to Curtis' Botanical magazine.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 1, 188[8]; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 2, 1888; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Smithsonian Institution
    Wash.,D.C., Typed L.S.:S[amuel] P.Langley,secretary. 1p. Enc.wanting. Returns acknowledgments for packages.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 3, 1888; 7x4-1/2; Michael, Helen Abbott, 1857-1904
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking why she has received no notices of meetings.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, March 5, 1888; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Concerning a key he has lost.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 5, 1888; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Diplomatic and consular service, German
    Phila., L.S.:Fred[eric]k Dalvigne,vice consul. 1p. Says he will transmit the enclosure to Prof.Steiner.
  - Letter to Helen C. de S. Abbott, March 5, 1888; 9x5-1/2; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., Dr.of L.S. 1p. Concerning why she has received no meeting notices. Refers to [D.G.] Brinton. For short-hand version of same letter, see same sheet as letter from Phillips to [J.S.] Price, March 5, 1888.
  - Letter to [J.Sergeant] Price, March 5, 1888; 9x5-1/2; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking advice in re [H.] Abbott's complaint that she does not receive meeting notices. Refers to [D.G.] Brinton. On same sheet is short-hand version of letter from H.Phillips to H.Abbott, March 5, 1888.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 6, 1888; 8x5; Bache, Richard Meade
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p. Enc.wanting. Concerning the word "conari" [in the Magellanic motto].
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 6, 1888; 3x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.and add. Asking if [F.] Fraley appointed W.A.Ingham one of the trustees of the Society's building fund.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], March 7, 1888; 8x5; Bache, Richard Meade
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p. concerning the word "conari" [in the Magellanic motto].
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], March 7, 1888; 8x5; Egypt Exploration Society
    Boston, A.L.S.:W[illia]m C.Winslow. 2p. Asking support for society's fund. Encloses a list of patrons of the fund (see in Pamphlets on archaeology).
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 8, 1888; 8x5; Bache, Richard Meade
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 3p. Criticism of "conari" in Magellanic motto. Refers to [F.?] Muhlenberg and [J.S.?] Price.
  - Letter to H.C[arvill] Lewis, March 10, 1888; 11x8-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p.,end. Enc.wanting. Forwards paper. Concerning Otto Meyer, and discusses [A.] Heilprin's antagonism towards him. Enclosed originally in letter from H.C. Lewis to H.Phillips, March 14, 1888.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 10, 1888; 8x5; Hagen, Hermann August, 1817-1893
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 3p. Concerning the Hessian fly. Refers to William Penn.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 11, 1888; 8x5; Bache, Richard Meade
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Concerning Mr.price [J.S.Price ?].
  - Letter to the President of the Magyar Tudomanyos Akademie, March 12, 1888; 7-3/4x9-3/4; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, Xerox copy of Printed L.S.: Fre[drick] Fraley. 1p. and end. (from the original in Magyar Tudomanyos Akademia konyvtara) Seeking cooperation in perfecting a universal language.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, March 14, 1888; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Lewis, Henry Carvill, 1853-1888
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. Sends paper by O.Meyer for publications by the Society. Refers to [E.D.] Cope. For enclosure, see letter from E.D.Cope to H.C.Lewis, March 10, 1888.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 15, 1888; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S. 2p. Enc.wanting. Financial matters. Concerning bill for engraver, and estimate for plate.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 15, 1888; 8x5; Du Bois, Patterson, 1847-1917
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Thanks for report on Volapük.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 15, 1888; 8x5; Rutland county historical society, Castleton, Vt.
    Rutland, A.L.S.:Henry Clark,secretary. 1p. Order for publication.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 16, 1888; 9x5-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    [Phila.] A.L.in 3rd P.S. 1p.and add. Enc.wanting Asking for favor.
  - Letter to [Edward D.Cope ?], March 16, 1888; 11x8-1/2; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Copy. Financial matters. Concerning the estimate for his plate. Refers to [J.S.] Price.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], March 17, 1888; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Financial matters. Says the artist must have cash.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, March 17, 1888; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Returns proof.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], March 17, 1888; 8x5-1/2; Marston, C. W.
    Cedar Junction, Kan., L.S. 1p. Asking for a History of Choctaw and Chickasaw Indians. Refers to C.Byington.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 19, 1888; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Phila., A.L.S.:Angelo Heilprin. 1p. Concerning [F.V.] Hayden.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S. [Henry Phillips], March 19, 1888; 7x4-1/2; Michael, Helen Abbott, 1857-1904
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Sends a synopsis of remarks she made at APS meeting, March 16, [1888].
  - Letter to Prof. E[dward] D.Cope, March 19, 1888; 11x8; T. Sinclair & Son
    Wash., D.C., L. 1p.,end.by E.D.Cope. Concerning his plates.
  - Letter to Henry S. Phillips [Henry Phillips], March 19, 1888; 9x6; Stowell, T. B. (Thomas Blanchard), 1846-1927
    Cortland, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p. Asking that proper dates be inserted in his paper.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 20, 1888; 3x5; Morris, J. Cheston (James Cheston), 1831-1923
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Concerning a quote from an ode by Horace.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 21, 1888; 6-1/2x4-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden,N.J., A.L.S. 4p. Thanks for letter of introduction. Concerning universal languages, Volapük, and an article in The Critic. Refers to D.Zeisberger.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 22, [1888]; 3x5; Chapman, Henry C. (Henry Cadwalader), 1845-1909
    [Phila.], A.L.on postal card S. 1p.,end.,and add. Asking for publication.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 22, 1888; 8x5; Hagen, Hermann August, 1817-1893
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 2p. Thanks for introduction to [S.W.?] Pennypacker. Concerning the Hessian fly. Refers to W.Penn and [G.H.] Horn.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, March 23, 1888; 10x8; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Concerning the circulars, and addressing of the envelopes.
  - Letter to Levytype co., March 23, [1888]; 3x5; Stowell, T. B. (Thomas Blanchard), 1846-1927
    Cortland, N.Y., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Thanks for proof of plates.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 26, 1888; 3x5; Stevenson, John J. (John James), 1841-1924
    New York, A.L.on postal card S. 1p.,end.,and add. Concerning [G.] Meneghini.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, March 28, 1888; 5x8; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Says all the letters are signed and ready to deliver to anyone he may send.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 28, 1888; 9-1/2x5-1/2; Levytype Co.
    Phila., L. 1p.and add.,end. Enc.wanting. Printing matters. Refers to [T.] Stowell.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 31, 1888; 8x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Printing matters. Concerning his manuscript.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] H.Horn, March 31, 1888; 9x5-1/2; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerning meeting of publication committee, and why he cannot attend.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 31, 1888; 5x4; Wagner, Samuel, 1842-
    A.L.S. 1p. Says he cannot attend meeting of publication committee today.
  - Memorandum pertaining to receipt of Society's publication, March, 1888; 3x5; Thompson, Henry, 1820-1904
    D.S. 1p.
  - Letter to Prof. J. P[eter] Lesley, April 2, 1888; 8x5; Foote, Albert E., 1846-1895
    [Phila.], L. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning a discount on publications purchased from Society. FILM403 FRAME99
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 2, 1888; 3x5; Horn, George H. (George Henry), 1840-1897
    [Phila.,]. A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Printing matter. Refers to [E.D.] Cope.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, April 4, 1888; 5x8; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Returns credential.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 4, [1888]; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Prestwich, Joseph, 1812-1896
    Shoreham, A.L.on postal card S.in 3rd P. 1p.,end., and add. Changes of address.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 5, [1888]; 9x5-1/2; James S. Earle & Sons
    Phila., L. 1p. Enc.wanting. Sends bill for removal of busts and pedestals from Society's rooms.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, April 5, 1888; 3x5; Foote, Albert E., 1846-1895
    [Phila.,] L. 1p.and add. Concerning P.Lesley. FILM 403 FRAME 100
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S. [Henry Phillips], April 6, 1888; 5x3; James, Edmund J. (Edmund Janes), 1855-1925
    [Phila.,] A.L.on postal card S. 1p.,end.,and add. Asking for copy of Society's constitution and rules.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 10, 1888; 9x5-1/2; Zamenhof, L. L. (Ludwik Lazar), 1859-1917
    Warsaw, L.S.:Samenhof. 1p. Copy in translation? Thanks for report on Volapük. Concerning a congress for an international language.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 12, 1888; 8x5; Doerflinger, Carl, 1843-
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p.,end. Concerning Volapuk.
  - Letter to Fred[eric]k Fraley, April 13, 1888; 10-1/2x8; Ryder, John A. (John Adam), 1852-1895
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.,end., and end. Agrees to prepare obituary of Joseph Zentmayer.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, April 14, 1888; 8x5; Gildersleeve, Basil L. (Basil Lanneau), 1831-1924
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p.,end.,and end. Declines to co-operate [in a congress for a universal language].
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, April 14, 1888; 10-1/2x8; Gilman, Daniel Coit, 1831-1908
    Baltimore, L.S. 1p.,end. Says he has referred the letter to the Johns Hopkins philological association.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 14, 1888; 3x5; Henshaw, Henry W. (Henry Wetherbee), 1850-1930
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Asking for report on Volapuk.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 14, 1888; 11x8-1/2; Oneida Historical Society at Utica
    Utica, N.Y., Printed L.filled in in ms.S.:C[harles] W. Darling (in rubber stamp). 1p. Thanks for reports on Volapük.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, April 14, 1888; 8x5; Stevens, W. LeConte (Walter LeConte), 1847-1927
    Brooklyn, A.L.S. 4p.,end. Concerning Volapük, universal languages. Refers to S. Haldeman, among others.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 16, 1888; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Axon, William E. A. (William Edward Armytage), 1846-1913
    Manchester, A.L.S. 2p.,end. Concerning a congress for a universal language.
  - Letter to [Frederick Fraley ?], April 16, 1888; 8x5; Du Bois, Patterson, 1847-1917
    Phila., A.L.S. 3p.,end.,and end. Agrees to prepare obituary of [James C.] Booth.
  - Letter to Fred[erick] Fraley, April 16, 1888; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Taylor, James Monroe, 1848-1916
    Poughkeepsie, N.Y., L.S.in another hand. 1p.,end. Declines to co-operate.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 17, 1888; 3x5; Toppan, Robert Noxon, 1836-1901
    Cambridge, [Mass.], A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Thanks for report of Volapük.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 20, 1888; 9-1/2x8; Bailey, Banks & Biddle Company (Philadelphia, Pa.)
    Phila., L. 1p. Asking if they may exhibit the [Magellanic] medal in their window.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, April 20, 1888; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    A.L.S.with initials. 1p. Enc.wanting. Concerning [J.] Cattell. Concerning interest on the Michaux legacy.
  - Letter to president of A.P.S.[Frederick Fraley], April 21, 1888; 8x5; University of South Carolina
    Columbia, A.L.S.:J[ohn] M.McBryde. 2p.,end.,and end Suggests Paris for congress on a universal language.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], April 23, 1888; 9x5-1/2; Edwards, T. C.
    Ancora,N.J., A.L.S. 2p. Concerning Volapük. Refers to [G.] Bauer, [J.] Schleyer, and C.Sprague.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 23, 1888; 9-1/2x6; Frazer, Persifor, 1844-1909
    [Phila.] A.L.S. 1p. Concerning publication of papers by Society. Refers to T.Sterry Hunt.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 23, 1888; 8x5; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerning his remarks on the water question.
  - Letter to president of A.P.S.[Frederick Fraley], April 23, 1888; 9-1/2x7-1/2; United States Naval Observatory. Nautical Almanac Office
    Wash.,D.C., Typed L.S.:S[imon] Newcomb. 1p.and end. Declines to co-operate in a congress for a universal language.
  - Letter to president of A.P.S.[Frederick Fraley], April 23, 1888; 8x5; Yorkshire Geological and Polytechnic Society
    Halifax, A.L.S.:James W.Davis. 1p.,end. Will co-operate in a congress for a universal language.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, April 23?, 1888; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S.with initials. 1p. Concerning mail. Concerning [J.] Cattell.
  - Memorandum pertaining to receipt of Society's report on Volapük, April 24, 1888; 4x7; British Museum
    D.S.:R.Garnett. 1p.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 24, 1888; 10x8; Philadelphia. Post office
    Phila., Typed L. 2p. Enc.wanting. Postal matter. Concerning delay in receipt of letter.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 25, 1888; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Smithsonian Institution
    Wash.,D.C., Typed L.S.: S[amuel] P.Langley,secretary. 1p. Concerning exchanges.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 25 (?), 188[8]; Price, John sergeant, 1831-1897
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, April 26, 1888; 8x5; Massachusetts Institute of Technology
    Boston, A.L.S.:Francis A.Walker. 2p.,end.,and end Concerning a congress for a universal language.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 27, 1888; 9x5-1/2; Hunt, Thomas Sterry, 1826-1892
    Wash., D.C., A.L.S. 1p. Offers papers on metalline minerals. Refers to P.Frazer.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 27, 1888; 3x5; Lamberton, John Porter, 1839-1917
    [Phila.], A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Concerning location of a town in Luxembourg.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 27, 1888; Hunt, T. Sterry
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 30, 1888; 9x5-1/2; Edwards, T. C.
    Ancora,N.J., A.L.S. 3p. Concerning Volapük, Spelin, [L.] Zamenhof, [J.] Schleyer, and an article in The Nation.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 30, 1888; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Jones, Charles H. (Charles Henry), 1848-1913
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Expects to pay the customs officer this morning.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 30, 1888; 8x5-1/2; Newberry Library
    Chicago, A.L.S.:W[illiam] F.Poole. 2p. Concerning exchanges. Concerning the Newberry library.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, April 30, 1888; 7x4-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Concerning Phillips' article. Refers to [J.B.] Gilder.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 1, 1888; 9-1/2x6-1/2; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Offers paper by Alfredo Dugés for publication in the Proceedings.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S. [Henry Phillips], May 1, 1888; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 1p. and add. Asking for announcement of his paper on Ear bones of the Permian Batrachia.
  - Letter to president of A.P.S.[Frederick Fraley], May 2, 1888; 13x8
    L.S.:[Sir] M[chael] Foster,secretary. 2p.,end. Concerning a congress for a universal language.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 3, 1888; 8x5; Elisha Mitchell Scientific Society (Chapel Hill, N. C.)
    Chapel Hill, A.L.S.:F[rancis] P.Venable. 2p. Thanks for publications.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, May 3, 1888; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    A.L.S. 2p. Enc.wanting. Approves his appointment to represent Society at University of Bologna celebration. Refers to [G.F.] Barker,[G.H.] Horn, and [J.S.] Price.
  - Letter to librarian of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], May 3, 1888; 9x5-1/2; Lea, M. Carey (Mathew Carey), 1823-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asking loan of Edinburgh philosophical magazines.
  - Letter to president of A.P.S.[Frederick Fraley], May 3, 1888; 8x5; Natural History Society of Northumberland, Durham, & Newcastle-upon-Tyne
    L.S.:W[illia]m Dinning. 2p.,end. Concerning a congress for a universal language.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 3, 1888; 10x8; Philadelphia. Post office
    Phila., Typed L.S.:W[illiam] F.Harrity, in another hand. 2p. Concerning delay in delivery of letter.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 4?, 1888; 8x5; Reynolds, Henry Lee
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S. 2p. Offers paper on Algonquin metal smiths for the Transactions.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], May 4, 1888; 8x5; Chase, Thomas Lincoln, 1831-1896
    Providence, R.I., A.L.S. 1p. Change of address.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 4, 1888; 9x5-1/2; Edwards, T. C.
    Ancora,N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Concerning Volapük, [G.] Bauer, [C.] Sprague, Mark Twain, [L.] Samenhof.
  - Letter to Fred[erick] Fraley, May 4, 1888; 7x4-1/2; Geological Society of London
    L.S.:W.S.Davis. 1p. Concerning [a congress for a universal language].
  - Letter to the President and fellow members of the American Philosophical Society., May 4, 1888; 8" x 12 1/2"; Haupt, Lewis M. (Lewis Muhlenberg), b. 1844